lifestyle.com.au 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy - lifestyle.com.au

Last Updated: April 2016

This is our Privacy Policy which sets out what personal information Foxtel* collects about you.

It sets out how we collect it, how we hold it, how we use it and who we disclose this information to. It explains what information we may collect from you when you use a Foxtel website, certain third party websites or a Foxtel Service. It also sets out how you may access and seek correction of your personal information or complain about a breach of your privacy. This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time if our practices change.

On our websites, you may find links to other websites not operated by us, including our partners' websites. This Privacy Policy doesn't apply to them - always check the Privacy Policy of any other website you enter.

You can navigate separate sections of this Privacy Policy through the links below.

  * **1\. What kinds of personal information do we collect and how?**
  * **2\. What information do we collect when you use a Foxtel website or a Foxtel Service?**
  * **3\. Do you have to identify yourself when you use a Foxtel website?**
  * **4\. Why do we collect the information and how do we use or disclose it?**
  * **5\. How can you request not to receive direct marketing?**
  * **6\. Who do we disclose your personal information to?**
  * **7\. Do we disclose your information overseas?**
  * **8\. How do we handle credit information?**
  * **9\. How do we hold your personal information and keep it secure?**
  * **10\. How can you seek access to, and correction of your information?**
  * **11\. How can you seek further information or complain about a breach of your privacy?**

## 1\. What kinds of personal information do we collect and how?

When you apply for a Foxtel Service** we collect personal information about you, and (where relevant) authorised representatives on your account. If you are an authorised representative on someone else's account, we may also collect information direct from you, for example if you provide your credit card information for use on an account. This enables us to connect you to your Foxtel Service, and allows us to provide and administer that service. This information may include your name, date of birth, contact details, credit card or bank account information, drivers licence number, Foxtel personal identification numbers (PINs) and other information relevant to the provision of your Foxtel Service.

We may also collect your personal information from you when you use a Foxtel Service, enter into one of our competitions or otherwise interact with us (such as through a Foxtel website, a Foxtel application or through social media). This may include information such as preference information and viewing habits and other usage data.

We may also collect your personal information from third parties where you have agreed with them that your information may be disclosed.

## 2\. What information do we collect when you use a Foxtel website or a Foxtel Service?

We collect information regarding activity on Foxtel websites and certain third party websites, such as the number of visitors to the website, the date and time of those visits, the number of pages viewed, navigation patterns and, where relevant, websites visited before visiting that website. On these websites, your visits are associated with cookies and/or local storage data which are unique identifiers that we use to store information about your current and previous visits. This information is collected by Foxtel or on Foxtel's behalf by various analytics companies. More information about how we use cookies, what information is collected and which third party sites we collect information from is available on the Foxtel Privacy Page which is located at <http://www.foxtel.com.au/about/privacy.html>.

When you use a Foxtel Service we collect information about your usage such as data and call usage, viewing or browsing habits as well as how you locate and watch content. This may include information on your favourite shows and channels.

If you are a Foxtel customer, we may link information about your viewing habits, website activity or usage with your account information.

This information provides Foxtel with statistics that we can use to analyse and improve our websites and our products and services. We may also use browsing and viewing habits data to deliver targeted marketing, advertising and content from Foxtel and third parties on Foxtel websites and Foxtel Services, as well as Foxtel advertising on third party sites, in each case relating to your preferences or interests.

For more information on how you can request not to receive targeted marketing and content based on your browsing or viewing habits please go to the Foxtel Privacy Page, which is located at <http://www.foxtel.com.au/about/privacy.html>.

## 3\. Do you have to identify yourself when you use a Foxtel website?

If you log into our website you will have identified yourself. Where possible, we allow you to use a pseudonym when contributing to our websites. If you wish to remain anonymous when you use a Foxtel website, do not sign in to the website or provide any information which may identify you.

## 4\. Why do we collect the information and how do we use or disclose it?

We collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information:

  * a. to assess your application for a Foxtel Service;
  * b. to connect you to, and provide and administer your Foxtel Service, including billing you, contacting you about your Foxtel Service, and resolving any disputes about your Foxtel Service;
  * c. to provide you with recommendations about use of your Foxtel Service and to personalise your experience with us;
  * d. to develop and enhance our products and services;
  * e. to manage network traffic, infrastructure use, quality and performance;
  * f. to monitor your data allowance in relation to specific Foxtel Services;
  * g. to conduct research and to plan and develop our product and marketing strategies;
  * h. to provide and operate our competitions, events and promotions;
  * i. to promote and market products and services of ours and our partners; and
  * j. to comply with our legal obligations including under the Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth), the Telecommunications (Interception and Access) Act 1979 (Cth) or any industry code or standard registered under the Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth).

## 5\. How can you request not to receive direct marketing?

If you do not wish to receive direct marketing communications from us please login to My Account to update your preferences, or contact us on 131 999 or by email at [privacy@foxtel.com.au](mailto:privacy@foxtel.com.au). If you have registered for specific newsletters or updates from Foxtel you may continue to receive these unless you opt-out from the specific communication using the link in that communication.

From time to time, Foxtel provides other avenues for requesting not to receive certain types of communications from Foxtel. To see these, please go to the Foxtel Privacy Page which is located at <http://www.foxtel.com.au/about/privacy.html>.

If you change your preferences, it may take some time for this change to take effect. Within this time, you may still receive direct marketing, however we will ensure that your preferences are updated as promptly as possible.

What happens if I don't allow you access to my personal information for direct marketing purposes?

We will always use any personal information we have on you with a strict level of confidence. We use it to ensure that we can talk to you about ways to enhance your Foxtel service, how to find the content you like, tell you about new services and applications and give you access to offers that we think will help you get the most out of your Foxtel Service. We will also use the information to provide you access to exclusive experiences that are linked to your preferences.

## 6\. Who do we disclose your personal information to?

We may disclose your personal information:

  * a. to authorised representatives on your account;
  * b. to entities who assist us in providing, administering, supporting, improving, promoting and marketing our products and services and our competitions, events and promotions, including suppliers, contractors, website hosting service providers, debt collectors, data storage and management companies including providers of cloud services, channel providers, and interactive advertisers;
  * c. to companies that promote and market, or conduct research to help us improve and target, our products and services;
  * d. to the Integrated Public Number Database Manager where the information is used to do things like write phone directories and assist with the dispatch for emergency services;
  * e. to law enforcement and national security agencies, other government and regulatory authorities and other organisations as required or authorised by law, including in relation to investigating and resolving disputes or complaints concerning your Foxtel Service; and
  * f. to third parties as required by law or in accordance with any industry code or standard registered under the Telecommunications Act 1997 (Cth).

We may also provide your personal information to the Foxtel Partners***, who will use it for similar purposes as us. How they use your personal information is subject to their privacy policies. If you do not wish us to provide your personal information to the Foxtel Partners, please contact us on 131 999 or by email at [privacy@foxtel.com.au](mailto:privacy@foxtel.com.au).

When you enter into a competition we are running or participate in a sponsored event, we may seek, as a condition of entry, consent to pass your information to a promoter or sponsor of the competition or event. If we do this, we will notify you at the time of entering into the competition or event with us.

## 7\. Do we disclose your personal information overseas?

We may disclose your personal information to third parties overseas who provide services to us, including to the United Kingdom and North America and to our customer service contractors located in the Philippines, South Africa and India.

We may also disclose your personal information overseas where a partner or sponsor of a competition or event we are running is located overseas. The countries where they are located vary. If we do this, we will notify you at the time of entering into the competition or event with us.

## 8\. How do we handle credit information?

In certain very limited circumstances we may be a credit provider to you. In these circumstances, the identification information we collect about you (your name, date of birth and address) is also "credit information" (as defined in the Privacy Act). We do not collect credit information from, or disclose it to, any credit reporting bodies.

We will handle your identification information that is credit information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In particular, please refer to the following sections:

  * **1\. What kinds of personal information do we collect and how?**
  * **4\. Why do we collect the information and how do we use or disclose it?**
  * **7\. Do we disclose your information overseas?**
  * **10\. How can you seek access to, and correction of your information?**
  * **11\. How can you seek further information or complain about a breach of your privacy?**

## 9\. How do we hold your personal information and keep it secure?

We hold your personal information in a combination of electronic and hard copy files. We may store your personal information with a third party data storage provider.

We may combine personal information we receive about you with other information we hold about you. This includes information received from third parties.

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we hold is protected from misuse, interference and loss, and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure by the use of various methods, including secure storage. Where we store your personal information with a third party data storage provider, we require them to keep it secure and only use or disclose it for the purpose for which it was provided.

Please contact us immediately if you become aware or have reason to believe there has been any unauthorised use of your personal information that we hold.

## 10\. How can you seek access to, and correction of, your personal information?

If you would like to find out what information we have about you, please contact us on 131 999 or by email at [privacy@foxtel.com.au](mailto:privacy@foxtel.com.au). We will ask that you put your request for access in writing and provide us with proof of your identity. You may be charged an administration fee when we provide you with the requested information to cover our time and postage and handling or retrieval costs.

We will generally provide you with access to your personal information that we have about you, but sometimes that will not be possible, in which case we will give you a written notice explaining why.

If you think that any personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete, out-of-date or irrelevant, you may ask us to correct it. We will take reasonable steps to correct it unless we disagree with your reasons. If we refuse to correct your personal information we will give you a written explanation why.

## 11\. How can you access further information or complain about a breach of your privacy?

If you believe that we have breached your privacy or have any questions in relation to this Privacy Policy, you can contact us on 131 999 or by email at [privacy@foxtel.com.au](mailto:privacy@foxtel.com.au) or write to the Foxtel Privacy Officer at PO Box 612, Moonee Ponds, Victoria, 3039.

We will investigate any complaint, and notify you of our decision in relation to the complaint, as soon as practicable after it is received. If we are unable to satisfactorily resolve your concerns about our handling of your personal information, you can contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

* Foxtel means Foxtel Management Pty Limited and all its subsidiaries, and any company or entity that is wholly owned (directly or indirectly) by the Foxtel Partnership **** including those companies which provide the Foxtel owned channels and Foxtel products and services.

** Foxtel Service means the product/s and/or service/s supplied by Foxtel which you apply for, purchase, subscribe to, or use.

***Foxtel Partners means News Australia Pty Limited and Telstra Media Pty Limited and any of their related companies or affiliates.

****Foxtel Partnership means the partnership between Sky Cable Pty Limited and Telstra Media Pty Limited
